Guide to the James McCourt and Vincent Virga Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal and Professional Papers, Series IV; 16; (16 boxes)
  - McCourt notes
    - Untitled (microcassette), undated; 1; This microcassette was found to be blank. No digitized files were created. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361785)
    - "Carmencita, The Lord Mayor" (microcassette), undated; 1; 00:45:20; There is high background noise on the cassette. The program ends abruptly. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099361793)
  - Miscellaneous notes, correspondence, printed matter, 2 (Box 41)
  - McCourt correspondence (Box 41)
  - McCourt royalty statements (Box 41)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous notes, correspondence (Box 42)
  - Review of Superstar in a Housedress (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous notes, correspondence, 2 (Box 42)
  - McCourt correspondence (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous notes, correspondence (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous notes, memorabilia (Box 42)
  - Review of Delancey's Way (Box 42)
  - Notes (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 42)
    6 computer disks
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0004.
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0014. Verbal Music
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0015. Tel +
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0016. Vietnam & compass
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0017.
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0018.
  - Virga correspondence (Box 42)
  - Virga lectures, 2009 (Box 42)
    3 computer disks
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0005. Vincent, Virga. Ancient Maps and the Religions of the World
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0019. Vincent Virga. Why is Europe a Continent?
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0020. Vincent Virga. Maps as Cultural Landscapes.
  - McCourt correspondence (Box 42)
  - Reviews, McCourt correspondence, 1 (Box 42)
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0006. Bookworm, producer and host: Michael Silverblatt featuring James McCourt
    Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0021. Los Angeles Times. Festival of Books.
  - Virga correspondence (Box 42)
  - Printed material (Box 42)
  - Financial records (Box 42)
  - McCourt correspondence, notes (Box 42)
  - McCourt notes for "This and That" (Box 42)
  - McCourt book contract and business correspondence (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
  - PEN Award Committee (Box 42)
  - What's for Dinner: Intro to NYR Books (Box 42)
  - Virga correspondence, 2 (Box 43)
  - Virga resume (Box 43)
  - Newspaper clipping (Box 43)
  - Virga notes (Box 43)
  - Virga correspondence, 2 (Box 43)
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0007; Cartographia - C-SPAN Book TV.
  - Neal Peters (Box 43)
  - Printed material (Box 43)
  - Virga correspondence, carthographia reviews (Box 43)
  - Virga correspondence, reviews, 3 (Box 43)
  - Newspaper clippings, printed material, miscellaneous notes (Box 43)
  - Leonard Silliman's "New Faces of '56" (Box 43)
  - Homage to Gerald Moore (Box 43)
  - Charley's Aunt by Brandon Thomas (Box 43)
  - Playbills (Box 43)
  - Printed opera/ballet material (Box 43)
  - Playbills, 7 (Box 43)
  - Playbills (continued), 5 (Box 44)
  - Theater / ballet programs, 2 (Box 44)
  - Virga correspondence (Box 44)
  - Birthday cards (Box 44)
  - Postcards (Box 44)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence, memorabilia (Box 44)
  - Family memories (Box 44)
  - Virga correspondence, 3 (Box 45)
  - The Bona Venture, 2 (Box 45)
  - James Dean (Box 45)
  - Virga correspondence, 2 (Box 45)
  - Lindenhurst High School playbills (Box 45)
  - Virga report cards (Box 45)
  - Theater memorabilia (Box 45)
  - Playbills and notes (Box 45)
  - Theater memorabilia (Box 45)
  - A Chance to Die, 1963 (Box 45)
  - In the Middle of Yesterday, 1964 (Box 45)
  - Sorry, Wrong Number, 1962 (Box 45)
  - Postcard from Angus Wilson to Virga (Box 45)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 45)
  - McCourt / Virga postcards (Box 45)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 46)
  - Letters from Gilbert Sorrentino to McCourt (Box 46)
  - 1958 Loughlinite (Box 46)
  - John Fandel (Box 46)
  - Letter from Sean Andrew Heaney to McCourt (Box 46)
  - Jerry Lang & Cherry Grove drag show programs (Box 46)
  - McCourt passport (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 46)
  - Resume PDF
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0008.
  - Reviews (Box 46)
  - Printed material (Box 46)
  - Bette Davis Foundation (Box 46)
  - Opera News (Box 46)
  - Queer Street (Box 46)
  - Greenwich Village at Night (Box 46)
  - Commencement speech (Box 46)
  - Vincent Virga: a life in pictures (Box 46)
  - Darragh Park (Box 46)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence, reviews (Box 46)
  - M. Monastyrsky, Some Remarks to "Mathematics at the Turn of the Millenium" (Box 46)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous printouts (Box 46)
  - Reviews (Box 46)
  - Postcards (Box 46)
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0009. Yale School of Drama, The Yale Rep Legacy.
  - Hedda Gabler (Yale Review) (Box 46)
  - Research for Kaye's home (Box 46)
  - "Bettane" research (Box 46)
  - McCourt / Virga correspondence (Box 46)
  - McCourt's love sonnets to Virga, 1964-1965 (Box 47)
  - McCourt correspondence (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous notes by McCourt (Box 47)
  - Glenn J (Box 47)
  - McCourt correspondence, miscellaneous notes (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous notes by McCourt (Box 47)
  - Jack Scalia: male model (Box 47)
  - Deborah Voigt (Box 47)
  - Glenn V. (Box 47)
  - Reviews of McCourt's books (Box 47)
  - Festival of Books, Reviews by McCourt, other miscellaneous (Box 47)
  - Dublin Millennium, 2 (Box 47)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 47)
  - Printed material, 2 (Box 47)
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0010. Stardust: the Bette Davis Story
  - McCourt's Now Voyagers, uncorrected galleys (Box 47)
  - McCourt reviews and other printed material (Box 47)
  - Film Comment, 3 (Box 48)
  - Christopher Street (Box 48)
  - New Yorker (Box 48)
  - Printed material (Box 48)
  - McCourt notes, 3 (Box 48)
    Computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.41568.0011.
  - McCourt notes (continued) (Box 49)
  - Playing cards, 3 (Box 49)
  - Delancey's Way
  - Time Remaining
  - Victoria de los Angeles
  - Community Theater Company
  - Childhood memorabilia
  - Lynn Goldberg book party for NYRB reissue of Mawrdew (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous Ireland pictures (Box 49)
  - McCourt's 60th birthday (Box 49)
  - Ireland (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 49)
  - Virga portraits (Box 49)
  - Virga family meeting McCourt, 1964 (Box 49)
  - McCourt photographs, 1964 (Box 49)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, postcard, notes (Box 49)
  - McCourt portraits (Box 50)
  - McCourt and Virga portraits (Box 50)
  - Various portraits (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous pictures (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 2 (Box 50)
  - Portraits (Box 50)
  - The Jimmy & Vincent show (Box 50)
  - Delancey's Way broadside
  - Gaywyck broadside
  - A Comfortable Corner broadside
  - McCourt photographs (Box 50)
  - McCourt portraits, 2 (Box 50)
  - Victoria de los Angeles
  - Queer Street review
  - Virga portraits (Box 50)
  - Childhood memorabilia, 8 (Box 50)
- Oversize Material, 3.33; (14 boxes)
  - Time Out of Mind (from Series I) (Box 51 Oversize)
  - Time Remaining (from Series I) (Box 51 Oversize)
  - Remembrance (from Series I) (Box 51 Oversize)
  - Histrionics (from Series I) (Box 51 Oversize)
  - Remembrance (from Series I) (Box 52 Oversize)
  - The Four Green Fields (from Series I) (Box 52 Oversize)
  - Principal Photography (from Series I) (Box 52 Oversize)
  - Do the Work As It Was Meant To Be Done (from Series I) (Box 52 Oversize)
  - Time out of Mind (from Series I) (Box 52 Oversize)
  - Something Sensational on the Train (from Series I), 2 (Box 52 Oversize)
  - New Yorker short stories (from Series I) (Box 53 Oversize)
  - Immortal She (from Series I), 2 (Box 53 Oversize)
  - Histrionics (from Series I) (Box 53 Oversize)
  - Delancey's Way (from Series I) (Box 53 Oversize)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchz (from Series I) (Box 53 Oversize)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (from Series I) (Box 53 Oversize)
  - All About Everyone Now (from Series I) (Box 54 Oversize)
  - Histrionics (from Series I), 2 (Box 54 Oversize)
  - I Go Back To the Mais Oui (from Series I) (Box 54 Oversize)
  - Manhattan College Players present in Smith Auditorium... Charley's Aunt... (from Series I) (Box 54 Oversize)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (from Series I), 1983 (Box 54 Oversize)
  - Time Out of Mind (from Series I) (Box 54 Oversize)
  - James McCourt (from Series III) (Box 54 Oversize)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (from Series I), 2 (Box 55 Oversize)
  - In Case It Is (from Series I) (Box 55 Oversize)
  - In Tin nan Og (from Series I) (Box 55 Oversize)
  - Pathetique / Time Remaining (from Series I) (Box 55 Oversize)
  - Time Out of Mind (from Series I) (Box 55 Oversize)
  - A Comfortable Corner (from Series II) (Box 56 Oversize)
  - Gaywyck (from Series II) (Box 56 Oversize)
  - James McCourt (from Series III) (Box 56 Oversize)
  - For Yonder Glows a Truly Brilliant Star (from Series I) (Box 57 Oversize)
  - Seven Monologues for the Climax of Snow Country (from Series I) (Box 57 Oversize)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (from Series I) (Box 57 Oversize)
  - Dust jacket for The Eighties: Images of America (from Series II) (Box 57 Oversize)
  - The Pound Net (from Series II) (Box 57 Oversize)
  - Now Voyagers (from Series I), 9 (Box 58 Oversize)
  - Now Voyagers (continued) (from Series I), 8 (Box 59 Oversize)
  - Now Voyagers (continued) (from Series I), 6 (Box 60 Oversize)
  - Wayfaring at Waverly in Silver Lake (from Series I) (Box 61 Oversize)
  - Miscellaneous (from Series IV) (Box 62 Oversize)
  - Mawrdew Czgowchwz (from Series IV) (Box 62 Oversize)
  - Carthographia (from Series II), 2007 (Box 62 Oversize)
  - Delancey's Way (from Series IV) (Box 63 Oversize)
  - Time Remaining (from Series IV) (Box 63 Oversize)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (from Series IV) (Box 63 Oversize)
  - Community Theater Company (from Series IV) (Box 63 Oversize)
  - McCourt portraits (from Series IV) (Box 63 Oversize)
  - Childhood memorabilia (from Series IV) (Box 63 Oversize)
  - Delancey's Way broadside (from Series IV) (Box 64 Oversize)
  - Gaywyck broadside (from Series IV) (Box 64 Oversize)
  - A Comfortable Corner broadside (from Series IV) (Box 64 Oversize)
  - Victoria de los Angeles (from Series IV) (Box 64 Oversize)
  - Queer Street review (from Series IV) (Box 64 Oversize)
- Computer media, 0.42; (1 box)
  Box 65 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Bookworm Prod/Host Micheal Silverblat featuring: James McCourt I Recorded: 01/23/04 KCRW 89.9 www.kcrw.com, 2011-genm-41568-0001; 1 (Box 65)
    Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0002; 1 (Box 65)
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0003; 1 (Box 65)
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0004; 1 (Box 65)
  - Vincent Virga "Ancient Maps and the Religions of the World" UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL MISSOURI March 3, 2009 11:00 a.m., 2011-genm-41568-0005; 1 (Box 65)
  - BOOKWORM Producer and Host: Michael Silverblatt featuring: James McCourt Recorded: 10/12/07 KCRW 89.9 www.kcrw.com, 2011-genm-41568-0006; 1 (Box 65)
  - Cartograhia - C-SPAN Book TV, 2011-genm-41568-0007; 1 (Box 65)
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0008; 1 (Box 65)
  - Yale School of Drama The Yale Rep Legacy, 2011-genm-41568-0009; 1 (Box 65)
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0010; 1 (Box 65)
  - IUU 1-4, 2011-genm-41568-0011; 1 (Box 65)
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0012; 1 (Box 65)
  - BOOKWORM Prod/Host: Micheal Silverblat featuring: James McCourt identity Recorded: 01/23/04 KCRW 89.9 www.kcrw.com, 2011-genm-41568-0013; 1 (Box 65)
  - Verbal Music, 2011-genm-41568-0014; 1 (Box 65)
  - tel +, 2011-genm-41568-0015; 1 (Box 65)
  - formatted Vietnam + compass roses, 2011-genm-41568-0016; 1 (Box 65)
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0017; 1 (Box 65)
  - [no label information], 2011-genm-41568-0018; 1 (Box 65)
  - Vincent Virga "Why is Europe a Continent?" UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL MISSOURI March 4, 2009 11:00 a.m., 2011-genm-41568-0019; 1 (Box 65)
  - Vincent Virga "Maps as Cultural Landscapes" UNIVERSITY OF CENTRAL MISSOURI March 3, 2009 3:30 a.m., 2011-genm-41568-0020; 1 (Box 65)
  - Los Angeles Times FESTIVAL OF BOOKS IN ASSOCIATION WITH UCLA Tenth Anniversary April 23-24 2005 1024 From Aristo to Stonewall & Beyond: Gay Literature Now, 2011-genm-41568-0021; 1 (Box 65)